<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on Tring Bellringers</title><link>https://tringbells.org/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on Tring Bellringers</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tringbells.org/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A new ringer's story</title><link>https://tringbells.org/news/newringer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tringbells.org/news/newringer/</guid><description>In May 2023 I climbed the ancient spiral staircase of the Tring tower for the first time and entered a new world beyond my imagining. Since then, it’s been a challenging journey, with a mixture of trepidation, fascination, enjoyment, and frustration. Overall, I’m pleased to be making steady progress.
I’ve always found pleasure in hearing church bells. If driving past a ringing tower I would habitually lower the car window to hear better.</description></item><item><title>Ringing for the King's Coronation</title><link>https://tringbells.org/news/coronation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tringbells.org/news/coronation/</guid><description>Ring for The King In Tring! was the enticing recruitment slogan put about by the Tower Captain of Tring tower in preparation for the Coronation of King Charles, I took the opportunity to commit myself to mastering that technique, as so many before me had, of that co-ordination of body and brain that seems so effortless when done by practiced ringers.
All I knew then about church bells was hearing their impressive, sonorous sound calling out over the town with their rung messages.</description></item><item><title>Visit by Halton explorer scouts</title><link>https://tringbells.org/news/scouts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tringbells.org/news/scouts/</guid><description>Fifteen members of the 1st Halton (RAF) Red Kite ESU with their leaders climbed the 36 step circular stairs to be welcomed to the ringing room by eight enthusiastic Tring ringers.
The fifteen split in to three smaller groups to visit the belfry in turn (more steps up!) where the concept of bells being ‘up’ or ‘down’ was explained, questions answered and, after donning ear defence, a bell was rung to demonstrate ‘full circle’ ringing (the bell rotates on its bearings through a full circle).</description></item><item><title>In memoriam — HM Queen Elizabeth II</title><link>https://tringbells.org/news/queen_funeral/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tringbells.org/news/queen_funeral/</guid><description>Proclamation - 10th Rung following the Proclamation of His Majesty, King Charles III Eve of funeral - 18th Rung fully muffled for a special Evensong on the eve of the funeral of Her Majesty, Queen Elizabeth II Funeral day - 19th Tolling tenor half muffled an hour before the funeral service of Her Majesty, Queen Elizabeth II</description></item><item><title>Ringing for the Platinum Jubilee</title><link>https://tringbells.org/news/jubilee/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tringbells.org/news/jubilee/</guid><description>The following ringing took place on Friday the 3rd of June.
70 of Queens Call changes Rounds and Call Changes Quarter peal attempt</description></item><item><title>Return to ringing after the Covid lockdown</title><link>https://tringbells.org/news/covid_return/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tringbells.org/news/covid_return/</guid><description>The team were very happy to be able to return to the tower after an extended period of being unable to do so. Albeit with a cold breeze and masks!</description></item><item><title>700th Anniversary of Tring's market charter</title><link>https://tringbells.org/news/700_charter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tringbells.org/news/700_charter/</guid><description>The bells of SS Peter &amp;amp; Paul, Tring have played their part in commemorating the 700th anniversary of the granting in 1315 By Edward II of the Charter for market to be held in Tring.
A peal1 of 5183 changes of Tring Surprise Major was rung at the beginning of the year.
At the beginning of June local ringers rang 1315 changes of Grandsire triples.
On the morning of June 29th (the patronal festival), a peal of 5088 changes of Tring Delight Major was rung and before the special evening service that day we rang a touch of 700 Grandsire and Plain Bob doubles as the civic dignitaries made their way to the church.</description></item></channel></rss>